FERNANDO MARTURET

WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT 786-859-5887 fernando.martu@gmail.com https://www.marturet.tech 668 Crystal Dr, Hendersonville, NC, 28791 SKILLS Technologies: HTML, CSS, TypeScript, NodeJS, Bubble.io, Git, Python Libraries: React, Express, MaterialUI,

Fluent in Spanish

EDUCATION

B.S in Psychology

TailwindCSS

mySQL

Florida International University

Databases: MongoDB, PostgresSQL,

2014-2018

PROFILE

Though I am not formally educated in Computer Science, I have had the pleasure of working alongside very talented software engineers for the last two years. I have worked on many personal projects as well as enterprise grade applications with a variety of front and backend technologies. I have worked with codeless tools like Bubble.io and can leverage the ability to build UIs quickly with such tools, while still knowing how to implement solutions with code. I have also familiarized myself with time tracking and version control software and worked with multiple developers of different backgrounds and specialties.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer

Lakeholdings (Fletcher, NC)

2022-present

- Led the development and maintenance of diverse web applications, utilizing a technology stack encompassing HTML, CSS, TypeScript, NodeJS, Python and Git.
- Contributed significantly to the growth of Canvasprints.com by actively
 participating in the development of the company's Management Information
 System (MIS) that tracks employee efficiency and monitors products/orders
 throughout the production process.
- Integrated with APIs and hardware to decrease manual labor in key steps of production and fulfillment.
- Developed Python scripts to automate key company processes and streamline operational workflows.
- Worked with databases such as MongoDB, PostgresSQL, and mySQL.
- Learned the importance of form validation in order to maintain clean and manageable databases long term
- Adopted, improved and maintained legacy codebases
- Cleaned and restructured existing databases using Python.
- Extended functionality of Bubble with NodeJS, Python and Vanilla Javascript to bypass data management and other limitations within the nocode platform.

Social Media/Sales Representative

OceanX (Arden, NC)

2018-2021

- Actively engaged with customers through various social media platforms to enhance brand presence and build positive relationships.
- Monitored and responded to customer inquiries, comments, and feedback on social media, contributing to a more dynamic and customer-centric online presence.
- Demonstrated in-depth knowledge of multiple product lines, enabling the provision of accurate and detailed information to customers.
- Conducted product demonstrations and provided recommendations tailored to customer needs, contributing to increased customer satisfaction and loyalty.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to streamline communication and ensure a seamless customer experience from sales inquiries to issue resolution.
- Worked closely with marketing teams to create and share engaging content on social media platforms, driving awareness and interest in the company's products.